<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WebApplicationTest>
	<TestDescription name="MediaWiki multiple remote vulnerabilities" version="0.1" released="20080307" updated="20140305" protocol="FTP" mayproxy="false" affects="server" severity="high" alert="success" type="Configuration">
		<WASPDescription BindAlertToFile="0" CrawlerProcessingMode="ParseOnly" TargetFormat="" Target="" ModuleName="" Request="" Response="" FullResponse="" DetailsFormat="" Details="" AuthType="0" AuthName="" AuthPass="" CompInfo="" DetaliedInformation="" AlertTags="known_vulnerabilities" CVE="CVE-2012-4377,CVE-2012-4378" CWE="CWE-79" CVSSVer="2.0" CVSSScore="5.0" CVSSDescr="AV:N/AC:L/Au:N/C:N/I:P/A:N/E:POC/RL:OF/RC:C" CVSSScoreTemp="4.0" CVSSScoreEnv="3.9" CVSS3Descr="CVSS:3.0/AV:N/AC:L/PR:N/UI:N/S:U/C:N/I:L/A:N"></WASPDescription>
		<Copyright></Copyright>
		<Description>MediaWiki 1.19.2 and 1.18.5 are fixing 6 security related bugs that could affect users of
MediaWiki. [break]

[ul]
[li]
Wikipedia administrator Writ Keeper discovered a stored XSS (HTML
injection) vulnerability. This was possible due to the handling of
link text on File: links for nonexistent files. MediaWiki 1.16 and
later is affected. For more details, see &lt;https://bugzilla.wikimedia.org/show_bug.cgi?id=39700&gt;[/li]
[li]
User Fomafix reported several DOM-based XSS vulnerabilities, made
possible by a combination of loose filtering of the uselang parameter,
and JavaScript gadgets on various language Wikipedias. For more
details, see &lt;https://bugzilla.wikimedia.org/show_bug.cgi?id=37587&gt;
[/li]
[li]
During internal review, it was discovered that CSRF tokens,
available via the api, were not protected with X-Frame-Options
headers. This could lead to a CSRF vulnerability if the API response
is embedded in an external website using an iframe. For more details,
see &lt;https://bugzilla.wikimedia.org/show_bug.cgi?id=39180&gt;
[/li]
[li]
During internal review, it was discovered extensions were not always
allowed to prevent the account creation action. This allowed users
blocked by the GlobalBlocking extension to create accounts. For more
details, see &lt;https://bugzilla.wikimedia.org/show_bug.cgi?id=39824&gt;
[/li]
[li]
During internal review, it was discovered that password data was
always saved to the local MediaWiki database, even if authentication
was handled by an extension, such as LDAP. This could allow a
compromised MediaWiki installation to leak information about user's
LDAP passwords. Additionally, in situations when an authentication
plugin returned false in its strict function, this would allow old
passwords to be used for accounts that did not exist in the external
system, indefinitely. For details on how to clean up the data leakage,
see: &lt;https://bugzilla.wikimedia.org/show_bug.cgi?id=39184&gt;
[/li]
[li]
During internal review, it was discovered that metadata about
blocks, hidden by a user with suppression rights, was visible to
administrators. For more details, see
&lt;https://bugzilla.wikimedia.org/show_bug.cgi?id=39823&gt;
[/li]
[/ul]</Description>
		<ApplicableTo>
			<Platform>
				<OS>*</OS>
				<Arch>*</Arch>
			</Platform>
			<WebServer>*</WebServer>
			<ApplicationServer>*</ApplicationServer>
		</ApplicableTo>
		<Impact>HTML Injection, abuse of functionality.</Impact>
		<Recommendation>Update to MediaWiki  1.19.2 and 1.18.5.</Recommendation>
	</TestDescription>
</WebApplicationTest>