<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<WebApplicationTest>
	<TestDescription name="Zabbix SQL injection" version="0.1" released="20080307" updated="20140225" protocol="FTP" mayproxy="false" affects="server" severity="high" alert="success" type="Configuration">
		<WASPDescription BindAlertToFile="0" CrawlerProcessingMode="ParseOnly" TargetFormat="" Target="" ModuleName="" Request="" Response="" FullResponse="" DetailsFormat="" Details="" AuthType="0" AuthName="" AuthPass="" CompInfo="" DetaliedInformation="" AlertTags="sql_injection" CVE="CVE-2013-5743" CWE="CWE-89" CVSSVer="2.0" CVSSDescr="AV:N/AC:M/Au:N/C:P/I:P/A:P/E:POC/RL:OF/RC:C" CVSSScore="6.8" CVSSScoreTemp="5.4" CVSSScoreEnv="5.4" CVSS3Descr="CVSS:3.0/AV:N/AC:L/PR:N/UI:N/S:C/C:H/I:H/A:N"></WASPDescription>
		<Copyright></Copyright>
		<Description>Zabbix is the ultimate open source availability and performance monitoring
solution. SEC Consult Vulnerability Lab reported an SQL injection vulnerability in Zabbix versions &lt;= 2.0.8. [break][break]

By exploiting this SQL injection vulnerability, an authenticated attacker (or
guest user) is able to gain full access to the database. This causes a
privilege escalation to power users as well as a possible compromise of the
database and operating system the database is running on.[break][break]

Because of the functionalities Zabbix offers, an attacker with admin
privileges could be able (depending on the actual configuration) to execute
arbitrary OS commands on the configured Zabbix hosts. This results in a severe
impact to the monitored infrastructure.[break][break]

Although the attacker needs to be authenticated in general, the system could
also be at risk if the adversary has no user account.  Zabbix offers a guest
mode which provides a low privileged default account for users without
password. If this guest mode is enabled, the SQL injection vulnerability can
be exploited unauthenticated.</Description>
		<ApplicableTo>
			<Platform>
				<OS>*</OS>
				<Arch>*</Arch>
			</Platform>
			<WebServer>*</WebServer>
			<ApplicationServer>*</ApplicationServer>
		</ApplicableTo>
		<Impact>The vulnerabilities allow an attacker to gain access to the database and execute arbitrary SQL statements.</Impact>
		<Recommendation>Upgrade to the latest version or apply the patches provided by vendor.</Recommendation>
		<Reference database="SEC Consult Vulnerability Lab Security Advisory 20131004-0" URL="https://www.sec-consult.com/fxdata/seccons/prod/temedia/advisories_txt/20131004-0_Zabbix_SQL_injection_v10.txt"></Reference>
		<Reference database="SQL injection vulnerabilities in the API and frontend" URL="https://support.zabbix.com/browse/ZBX-7091"></Reference>
		<Reference database="CVE-2013-5743" URL="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2013-5743"></Reference>
	</TestDescription>
</WebApplicationTest>